{
  "title": "3.1",
  "definitions": {
    "FROLIC": {
      "word": "FROLIC",
      "phonetic": "(frol'-ik)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to make merry, play happily, romp </p><p>To FROLIC is to play in a lighthearted, carefree way. The word is used especially about children or about people acting like children. </p><p>“I love to see children FROLIC at the beach.” </p><p>“She FROLICKED about the yard, singing happily.” </p><p>FROLIC can also be used as a noun. </p><p>“After their FROLIC in the snow they came inside, cold but happy.” </p><p>Usage: The past tense of FROLIC is spelled FROLICKED.</p>"
    },
    "CONGESTION": {
      "word": "CONGESTION",
      "phonetic": "(kQn-jes'-chQn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">overcrowding, overfullness </p><p>To CONGEST means to <i class=“def-ital\">overfill</i> or <i class=“def-ital\">overcrowd</i>. </p><p>“The subway trains are always CONGESTED at five o’clock in the evening.” </p><p>CONGESTION is the state of being overcrowded or too full. “Traffic CONGESTION” is when there are so many cars on a street that traffic becomes blocked. “Lung CONGESTION” is when the lungs become so full of fluid that it is difficult to breathe. </p><p>“So many people crowded onto the subway platform that the CONGESTION was terrible.” </p><p>“CONGESTION became so bad in the city that many people moved to the suburbs.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: CONGEST, v.</p>"
    },
    "VIOLATE": {
      "word": "VIOLATE",
      "phonetic": "(vl-ÔøΩIAt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to break, interfere with, treat badly </p><p>To VIOLATE a law or rule is to break it, to fail to keep it. </p><p>“If you VIOLATE this law, you will be sent to jail.” </p><p>“He VIOLATED our order to stay inside.” </p><p>In another sense, VIOLATE means “to treat in an improper manner.” The word is used especially about non- physical things like rights or dignity. </p><p>“His orders VIOLATE our basic human rights.” </p><p>“Bill didn’t like anyone to VIOLATE his privacy.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: VIOLATION, n.</p>"
    },
    "INTERMEDIATE": {
      "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
      "phonetic": "(in-tÔøΩ-mE'-dE-it)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">in the middle, in between </p><p> The <i class=“def-ital\">medi</i> part of INTERMEDIATE comes from the Latin word for <i class=“def-ital\">middle</i>, which is also the source of the word <i class=“def-ital\">medium</i>. Something that is INTERMEDIATE comes in the middle; it is, for example, between two stages, times, or extremes. </p><p>“He was too good for the beginners’ group, and not good enough for the advanced group, so they put him in the INTERMEDIATE group.” </p><p>“There are several INTERMEDIATE steps between starting the machine and getting the final product.”</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">inter-</i> under Prefixes and <i class=“def-ital\">-ate2</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "RECEPTION": {
      "word": "RECEPTION",
      "phonetic": "(ri-sep'-shQn)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a welcome, greeting </p><p>RECEPTION is the act of receiving. It is often used about the receiving of guests. </p><p>“I got a cool RECEPTION from the host when I arrived two hours late.” </p><p>A wedding RECEPTION is the formal receiving of guests after a wedding. RECEPTION is used for other kinds of receiving as well, like the receiving of radio or television signals. </p><p>“We had very poor RECEPTION on our TV until we bought an antenna.” On the Pretest, many people confuse RECEPTION with <i class=“def-ital\">farewell</i>, which is an exact opposite. </p><p>Other forms of the word: RECEPTIVE, adj.</p>"
    },
    "STEER": {
      "word": "STEER",
      "phonetic": "(stEr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to guide, lead, direct the course of </p><p>To STEER something is to guide it in a particular direction. The word can be used about physical objects like cars and boats and about conversations, interests, and the like. </p><p>“Jane STEERED the canoe with her paddle.” </p><p>“He STEERED us quickly through the crowded station.” </p><p>“You STEER a car by turning the STEERING wheel.” </p><p>“We tried to STEER him toward college, but he wanted to work after high school.”</p>"
    },
    "SUBSTITUTE": {
      "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
      "phonetic": "(suhb'-stÔøΩtUt)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to put in place of, take the place of, exchange </p><p>SUBSTITUTE is both a verb and a noun. To SUBSTITUTE something is to put or use it in place of something else. </p><p>“He SUBSTITUTED the fake painting for the real one.” </p><p>“You may SUBSTITUTE margarine for butter when you make this cake.” </p><p>When something SUBSTITUTES for something else, it takes the place of it. </p><p>“For a blind person, the other senses have to SUBSTITUTE for the sense of sight.” </p><p>A SUBSTITUTE is something that takes the place of something else. </p><p>“The coach sent Bill in as a SUBSTITUTE for the center.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: SUBSTITUTION, n.</p>"
    },
    "VICINITY": {
      "word": "VICINITY",
      "phonetic": "(vi-sin'-ÔøΩtE)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">neighborhood, surrounding area </p><p>The area surrounding a place is called the VICINITY. “In the VICINITY of the school” means “near the school” or “in the neighborhood of the school.” </p><p>“She lives in the VICINITY of the hospital. Her apartment is just across the street.” </p><p>“There are several grocery stores in the VICINITY.” </p><p>“The robber was seen leaving the VICINITY of the bank at two o’clock.”</p>"
    },
    "ABRUPT": {
      "word": "ABRUPT",
      "phonetic": "(ÔøΩbruhpt')",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">sudden, unexpected; curt, blunt </p><p>Something that is ABRUPT happens without warning. It occurs so suddenly that it is almost unpleasant. </p><p>“His departure was ABRUPT, to say the least. One minute he was talking to me, the next minute he was gone.” </p><p>ABRUPT is often used about people and their behavior. A person who is ABRUPT is brief almost to the point of rudeness in the way he acts or speaks. </p><p>“Mr. Ames has a rather ABRUPT manner that makes people feel he is eager to get rid of them.”</p>"
    },
    "EVIDENT": {
      "word": "EVIDENT",
      "phonetic": "(ev'-ÔøΩdÔøΩnt)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">clear, apparent, obvious, plain </p><p> EVIDENT comes from the Latin root <i class=“def-ital\">vid</i>, which means to <i class=“def-ital\">see</i>. <i class=“def-ital\">Vid</i> is also the source of the words <i class=“def-ital\">video</i> and <i class=“def-ital\">vision</i>. Something that is EVIDENT is easily seen; it is plain and clear. It can be clear either to the eye or to the mind. </p><p>“Her anger was EVIDENT from the way she went around slamming doors.” </p><p>“It became EVIDENT that our team just wasn’t good enough to win.” </p><p>“The man EVIDENTLY was wealthy; he lived in a mansion.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: EVIDENCE, n.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-ant</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "BAN": {
      "word": "BAN",
      "phonetic": "(ban)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to forbid </p><p>BAN means to <i class=“def-ital\">forbid</i>, “to give an order that something must not be done.” </p><p>“Cigarette smoking is BANNED in many restaurants.” </p><p>“Jim’s mother BANNED all yelling in the house.” </p><p>BAN is also a noun, and means “an order forbidding something,” a <i class=“def-ital\">prohibition</i>. </p><p>“The government put a BAN on buying or selling gold.” </p><p>“There was a BAN on driving during the emergency.”</p>"
    },
    "ENDURE": {
      "word": "ENDURE",
      "phonetic": "(en-dUr')",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to put up with, bear; to last, continue </p><p>ENDURE is related to the word <i class=“def-ital\">durable</i>. Both come from a Latin word that means <i class=“def-ital\">lasting</i>. ENDURE has two related meanings. The first is to <i class=“def-ital\">put up with</i>, especially with patience and for a long time. </p><p>“I can’t ENDURE listening to his complaints again.” </p><p>“Since you can’t change the weather, you’ll just have to ENDURE it.” </p><p>“That tree has ENDURED wind and rain and snow, and still it has survived.” </p><p>The second meaning is “to continue to exist” for a long time, to <i class=“def-ital\">last</i>. </p><p>“His desire to learn ENDURED throughout his life.” </p><p>“The belief that the Earth was the center of the universe ENDURED for centuries.” </p><p>Other forms of the word: ENDURANCE, n.</p>"
    },
    "FEUD": {
      "word": "FEUD",
      "phonetic": "(fyUd)",
      "pos": "n.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">a long, bitter quarrel </p><p>Note the pronunciation. A FEUD is a quarrel that goes on over a long period of time. It is always bitter and sometimes violent. </p><p>“They had forgotten what started the FEUD, but they were still angry with each other twenty years later.” </p><p>“The FEUD between the two families was never really settled.” </p><p>FEUD can also be used as a verb. </p><p>“The two neighbors FEUDED over the location of the fence.” </p><p>“He FEUDED with his brothers over his share of the inheritance.”</p>"
    },
    "FRISKY": {
      "word": "FRISKY",
      "phonetic": "(fris'-kE)",
      "pos": "adj.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">lively, playful, energetic </p><p>One meaning of the verb to FRISK is “to move about playfully.” </p><p>“The puppies FRISKED about on the lawn.” </p><p>FRISKY means “given to FRISKING,” <i class=“def-ital\">lively</i>, <i class=“def-ital\">playful</i>.  </p><p>“They thought the pony was too FRISKY, so they bought a slower, quieter one instead.” </p><p>“The old man started to feel a bit FRISKY on the bright spring morning.” </p><p>FRISKY is often confused with <i class=“def-ital\">friendly</i>, perhaps because the two words look alike. A pet or person could be both FRISKY and <i class=“def-ital\">friendly</i>, but the two words do not have the same meaning. </p><p>Other forms of the word: FRISK, v.</p>",
      "suffix": [
        "See <i class=“def-ital\">-y</i> under Suffixes."
      ]
    },
    "PAMPER": {
      "word": "PAMPER",
      "phonetic": "(pam'-pÔøΩr)",
      "pos": "v.",
      "deftext": "<p class=\"definition\">to spoil, indulge, humor, coddle </p><p>To PAMPER someone is to treat him or her with too much care and attention, to be excessively kind. The word almost always suggests that this is a bad thing, and that the person who is PAMPERED may become spoiled as a result. </p><p>“They PAMPER their children. They let them stay up late and eat nothing but desserts.” </p><p>“She decided to PAMPER herself and stay in bed till noon.” </p><p>“She was PAMPERED as a child, and now she can’t do anything for herself.”</p>"
    }
  },
  "id": "1",
  "exercises": [
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Let them FROLIC.",
          "answers": [
            "jump up",
            "sit still",
            "laugh loudly",
            "play merrily",
            "run fast"
          ],
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "play merrily"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Doesn't like CONGESTION.",
          "answers": [
            "joking",
            "loneliness",
            "overcrowding",
            "arguing",
            "heights"
          ],
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "overcrowding"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIOLATE the rule.",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "honor",
            "think about",
            "despise",
            "ignore"
          ],
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "break"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The INTERMEDIATE course.",
          "answers": [
            "final",
            "middle",
            "communications",
            "easy",
            "next"
          ],
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "middle"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Tremendous RECEPTION.",
          "answers": [
            "trick",
            "sympathy",
            "welcome",
            "favor",
            "farewell"
          ],
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "welcome"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To STEER it.",
          "answers": [
            "plan",
            "enter",
            "laugh at",
            "finish",
            "guide"
          ],
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "guide"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He SUBSTITUTED it",
          "answers": [
            "started",
            "did without",
            "exchanged",
            "supported",
            "weakened"
          ],
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "exchanged"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "From the VICINITY.",
          "answers": [
            "neighborhood",
            "hotel",
            "city",
            "church",
            "devil"
          ],
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "neighborhood"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABRUPT decision.",
          "answers": [
            "hard",
            "sudden",
            "evil",
            "stupid",
            "important"
          ],
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "sudden"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Quite EVIDENT.",
          "answers": [
            "true",
            "difficult",
            "unusual",
            "common",
            "clear"
          ],
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "clear"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Wanted to BAN it.",
          "answers": [
            "forget",
            "allow",
            "collect",
            "forbid",
            "destroy"
          ],
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "forbid"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We ENDURED his insults.",
          "answers": [
            "put up with",
            "hated",
            "were hurt by",
            "returned",
            "didn't listen to"
          ],
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "put up with"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Ended the FEUD.",
          "answers": [
            "long quarrel",
            "riot",
            "hatred",
            "world war",
            "tragedy"
          ],
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "long quarrel"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRISKY pets.",
          "answers": [
            "slow",
            "lively",
            "friendly",
            "bad-tempered",
            "fast"
          ],
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "lively"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "To PAMPER her.",
          "answers": [
            "dress",
            "punish",
            "bother",
            "spoil",
            "admire"
          ],
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "spoil"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-one",
      "id": "pretest"
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "Do people usually FROLIC at funerals?",
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is there likely to be CONGESTION on a desert island?",
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Does a person VIOLATE the law when he steals something?",
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would an expert have problems with something at an INTERMEDIATE level of difficulty?",
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a dog give you a warm RECEPTION?",
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a car be STEERED?",
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is margarine used as a SUBSTITUTE for butter?",
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is New York City in the VICINITY of Los Angeles?",
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a television program ended in the middle of a sentence, would its ending be ABRUPT?",
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If a person's anger is EVIDENT, is he hiding it very well?",
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "If someone tried to BAN baseball in the United States, would he be successful?",
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Would a lightning flash ENDURE for hours?",
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Can a FEUD be stopped?",
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Is a snail a FRISKY animal?",
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Do you PAMPER a small child by spanking him?",
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "false"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 1
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "The baby was laughing and splashing and FROLICKING in the bathtub.",
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "There was a lot of CONGESTION about what exactly we were supposed to do.",
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The prisoner claimed that his rights were VIOLATED because he wasn't allowed to speak to a lawyer.",
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Thomas had to take INTERMEDIATE-level Spanish over again.",
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "Magicians practice for a long time to become skillful in their RECEPTIONS.",
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "false"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She tried to STEER the conversation toward a more interesting subject, but everyone else wanted to talk about sports.",
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The store SUBSTITUTED a cheaper brand of paper for the one we ordered.",
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We couldn't see him, but we knew he was somewhere in the VICINITY.",
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She ABRUPTLY decided she didn't like the dance, and left immediately.",
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EVIDENTLY we didn't make the team; our names aren't on the list.",
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "As punishment, their parents placed a BAN on watching television.",
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "She was able to ENDURE the pain by taking aspirin three times a day.",
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "We refused to become involved in their silly FEUD.",
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "The children were having a FRISKY game of tag.",
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "true"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "He said that even though he was ill he didn't want to be PAMPERED.",
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "true"
        }
      ],
      "type": "tf",
      "id": 2
    },
    {
      "questions": [
        {
          "prompt": "FROLIC",
          "answers": [
            "play",
            "enjoy",
            "race"
          ],
          "word": "FROLIC",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "CONGESTION",
          "answers": [
            "crowding",
            "fullness",
            "finishing"
          ],
          "word": "CONGESTION",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VIOLATE",
          "answers": [
            "break",
            "ill-treat",
            "choose"
          ],
          "word": "VIOLATE",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "answers": [
            "middle",
            "edge",
            "center"
          ],
          "word": "INTERMEDIATE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "RECEPTION",
          "answers": [
            "greeting",
            "admiring",
            "receiving"
          ],
          "word": "RECEPTION",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "STEER",
          "answers": [
            "stop",
            "lead",
            "drive"
          ],
          "word": "STEER",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "answers": [
            "switch",
            "sell",
            "trade"
          ],
          "word": "SUBSTITUTE",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "VICINITY",
          "answers": [
            "sameness",
            "nearness",
            "neighborhood"
          ],
          "word": "VICINITY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ABRUPT",
          "answers": [
            "short",
            "sudden",
            "dangerous"
          ],
          "word": "ABRUPT",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "EVIDENT",
          "answers": [
            "plain",
            "probable",
            "obvious"
          ],
          "word": "EVIDENT",
          "correct": "1"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "BAN",
          "answers": [
            "prevent",
            "forbid",
            "argue"
          ],
          "word": "BAN",
          "correct": "2"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "ENDURE",
          "answers": [
            "agree",
            "continue",
            "bear"
          ],
          "word": "ENDURE",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FEUD",
          "answers": [
            "loneliness",
            "fight",
            "anger"
          ],
          "word": "FEUD",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "FRISKY",
          "answers": [
            "powerful",
            "playful",
            "spirited"
          ],
          "word": "FRISKY",
          "correct": "0"
        },
        {
          "prompt": "PAMPER",
          "answers": [
            "humor",
            "spoil",
            "respect"
          ],
          "word": "PAMPER",
          "correct": "2"
        }
      ],
      "type": "mc-all",
      "id": 3
    }
  ]
}